Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 1-86.)
  - French Underground
  - Friends of Democracy
  - Frisch, Max
  - Fritsch, Werner von, Freiherr
  - Frischauer, Leo
  - Fuchs, Klaus Emil
  - Fuller, J. F. C., "Justice or Revenge" (on Nuremberg)
  - Galantiere, Lewis
  - Gamelin, Maurice-Gustave, 2 folders)
  - The GAP
  - Gasperi, Alcide de
  - Gaulle, Charles de, 3 folders)
  - Gaulle, Pierre de
  - Gaus, Friedrich
    - General
    - Examination by Kempner (Box 24)
  - General clippings, 3 folders)
  - General data
  - Genocide
  - Geopolitics
  - George VI, 2 folders)
  - Georgia (U.S.S.R.)
  - Geneva Conventions, 2 folders)
  - Germ warfare
    - General
    - Charges against the U.S.
  - The German American
  - German Army
    - General
    - In the service of the West
  - German atomic research
  - German atrocities
    - Belgium
    - France
    - Greece
    - Norway
    - Poland, 3 folders) (Box 25)
    - U.S.S.R.
    - Yugoslavia
  - "German Atrocities throughout Europe", 3 folders)
  - German bestiality
  - German canal and river systems
  - German communists
  - German decartelization
  - German diplomacy
  - German editors in the U.S.
  - German fifth column journalism in the U.S.
  - German Foreign Office secret documents
  - German-French armistice
  - German General Staff corps
  - German generals
  - German peace treaties
  - German press in the U.S.
  - German prisoners in the U.S.
  - German resistance (July 20, 1944)
  - German-Soviet Agreement, April 25, 1958
  - German-Soviet relations. See Russo-German relations
  - German spies
  - German surrender
  - "German Tendencies of Aggression against the U.S." (J. E.)
  - German war aims, 1914
  - German war criminals (jurisdiction) (Box 26)
  - German whaling
  - Germans, Displaced
  - "Germans Forecast American Conquest Sixty Years Ago" (J. E.)
  - German war aims, 1914
  - Germans in the U.S. (scientists)
  - Germanic Library, Columbia University
  - Germany Today (communist newsletter)
  - "Germany's Record and World Security"
  - Gestapo, 2 folders)
  - Gettysburg Address
  - Ghettozeitungen
  - Giannini, Guglielmo
    - General
    - Empire
  - Gibraltar
  - "Gibt es ein anderes Deutschland?" (J. E.)
  - Gide, Andre
  - Gideonse, Harry D.
  - Giral, Jose - Government
  - Giraud, Henri-Honore
    - General
    - His own escape story
    - Obituaries
  - Giraudoux, Jean
  - Gisevius, Hans Bernhard
    - General
    - Affidavit for Weizsacker
  - Gitlow, Benjamin
    - General
    - On William Foster
  - Glaser, Kurt
  - Goebbels, Joseph
    - General
    - Death
    - Speeches
  - Goerdeler, Carl F.
    - General
    - On reasons why Germany lost the war
  - Gold, Harry
  - Goldberg, Louis P.
  - Goldmann, Nahum
  - Gomulka, Wladislaw
  - Gontard, Gert von
  - Goring, Hermann
  - Gotz, Abram. See Liber, Michel
  - Gould-Talleyrand, Duchess of
  - Gouzenko, Igor
  - Government periodicals
  - Government printer
  - Goverments in exile
  - Grand Coulee Dam
  - Grandi, Dino
  - Grau, Ramon
  - Greece
    - General
    - And Turkey (first report on aid)
  - Green, Reverend
  - Greenland
  - Grim, Friedrich, "Concerning the Necessity of a General Amnesty in Germany"
  - Gromyko, Andrei A.
  - "Die grosse Zwangsrepatriierung" (J. E.)
  - Grow, Robert
  - Guatemala
    - General
    - Communists in
  - Guderian, Heinz
  - Gumbel, E. J.
  - Gunther, Blair F.
  - Gunther, Otto Octave, 2 folders)
  - Gurian, W., "Permanent Features of Soviet Foreign Policy"
  - Habe, Hans (Janczi Bekessy)
    - General
    - "Unsere 'Liebesaffare' mit Deutschland"
  - Habsburg, Otto von
  - Hagen, Paul
  - Haidari
  - Halder, General
  - Halifax, Lord - Speeches
  - Hallstein, Walter, 3 folders)
  - Hamburger, Ludwig (Box 27)
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
  - Hamsun, Knut
  - Hanfstaengl, Ernst Sedgwick (Putzi)
  - Hard, William, "Eight Things to Do about the Soviet Union"
  - Harriman, W. Averell
  - Harvard University (Board of Overseers)
  - Hassel, Ulrich von
  - 'Hauptmann E. K.' (World War II espionage in Italy), 2 folders)
  - Hauser, Heinrich
  - Hawaii (claim to statehood)
  - "The Hawaii-Alaska Dilemma"
  - Hayek, Friedrich A.
  - Hazlitt, Henry, "Flaws in the Marshall Plan"
  - Healy, Thomas A.
  - Hearst family
  - Hecht, Ben
  - Heilige
  - Heym, Stefan
  - Heptisax
  - Hertzog, J. B. M.
  - Herald Tribune Forum
    - 1945
    - 1946, 2 folders)
    - 1947
    - 1953 (Box 28)
  - Hersey, John, "Hiroshima"
  - Hess, Rudolph
    - General
    - Excerpts
    - Gerlinde Haberl's petition to Nixon concerning Hess
  - Heuss, Theodor
  - Heydrich, Reinhard
  - Hicks, Granville. See Ross, Irvin
  - High-octane gas
  - Hilger, Gustav, "Die sowjetische Aussenpolitik von 1917 bis 1939"
  - Hiller, Kurt
  - Himmler, Heinrich
  - Hindus, Maurice
  - Hirohito
  - Hiss case (Nixon's speech)
  - Hitler, Adolf
    - Anti-Hitler plot
    - Chronology (by Adolf Lange)
    - Death story
    - "Hitler's Power in 1939"
    - Hitler redivivus
    - Speeches, addresses
    - Testament
    - "Hitler's Words"
  - Hlond, Cardinal (Box 29)
  - Hoare, Samuel, Sir
  - Hohenlohe, Franz
  - Hohenzollern
  - Holland
  - Holland, Robert
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - General
    - Library
    - Report, January and February 1949
    - Speeches
      - On American foreign policy in relation to the Soviet Union (5)
      - On speech making
      - Republican convention speech, 1952
      - Waldorf speech of April 27, 1950, and response
  - Hopkins, Harry L.
  - Horney, Karen
  - Houdek, Vladimir
  - Hughes, Howard
  - Hull, Cordell
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Balance of power
    - Memoirs
  - Human Events
  - Human rights
    - Article by Max Beer
    - Statement by Panama's delegation
  - Humbert, Crown Prince of Italy
  - Hungary
  - Hurley, Patrick J.
  - Hutson, John B.
  - Hyde Park, N.Y.
    - General
    - Material found there
  - Hyderabad
  - Hydrogen bomb, 3 folders)
  - ICCASP (Independent Cit. Comm. of the Arts, Sciences and Professions)
  - Ice cap
  - I.G. Farben
  - Immigration quotas
  - "Imperial Communism" (by Edward B. Wilcox)
  - India
  - India-Pakistan Agreement
  - Indian famine
  - Indian reservations (U.S.)
  - Indians in South Africa
  - Indochina (Box 30)
    - General
    - Conflict
  - Indonesia
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Communism made a crime
  - Industrial miracle
  - Inflation (American)
  - Information sources
  - Ingrim, Robert
  - Innitzer, Theodor
  - Institute of Fiscal and Political Education
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Hearings
    - News scoop
  - Intelligence Digest (Review of World Affairs)
  - Inter-American Conference, Mexico, 1945
  - International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO)
  - International Documentation Service
  - International Monetary Fund
  - International Peasant Union
  - International Police Force
  - International Publishers
  - International transfers of territory in Europe
  - Iran (Box 31)
    - General, 2 folders)
    - 1952
  - Iraq
  - "Is there Another Germany?" (J. E.)
  - Israel
    - General
    - Bond issue prospectus
    - Imperialistic
    - Treaty violations
  - Italian draft treaty
  - Italian front
  - Italy
    - General
    - Republican Fascist Government
    - Surrender
  - Izvestiia
  - Jack & Heintz
  - Jacksch, Wenzel
  - Jackson, C. D.
    - General
    - 'Cold War Chief'
    - Letter, Washington Post
  - Jackson, Robert H.
  - Jackson, William Eldred, "Putting the Nuremberg Law to Work"
  - James, Edwin
    - General
    - Obituaries
  - Japan
    - General
    - Coming betrayal of
    - Post-war
  - Japanese atrocities
  - Japanese Peace Treaty
  - Japanese spies in the Western Hemisphere
  - Jaspers, Karl
  - Jeff, Gladwyn, Sir
  - Jerusalem, Damages in
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - Jet propulsion
  - Jewish army
  - Jewish claims against Austria
  - Jewish Labor Committee
  - Jews
    - General
    - Behind the Iron Curtain, 3 folders)
    - In Germany
    - In Poland
    - Plans for
  - Joesten, Joachim
  - Johnson, Hewlett, Reverend. See Canterbury, Dean of
  - Johnston, Eric A.
  - Joliot-Curie, Frederic
  - Journalism in the U.S.
  - Judd, Walter
  - Jung, Carl Gustav
  - Jungk, Robert B., 3 folders)
  - Juristische Hinweise
  - Kaiser, Henry
  - Kaiser, Jacob
  - Kaltenborn, H. V. (Box 32)
  - Kamnitzer, Bernhard
  - Kantorowicz, Alfred, 2 folders)
  - Karaghiosov, Dimitri
  - Karoly, Michael, Count
  - Katz, Rudolf
  - Kashmir
  - Katanga (Congo)
    - General
    - August 8, 1960
    - Clippings, December 28, 1961-
    - Committee
    - History
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940 - Hearings - Official Report
    - Part 1
    - Part 3, Chicago, March 13 and 14, 1952
  - Katz-Suchy, Juliusz
  - Kautsky, Karl, "Wie der Weltkrieg enstand" (excerpts)
  - Kefauver Crime Report
  - Keitel, Wilhelm
  - Kellen, Konrad
  - Kempner, Robert M. W.
  - Kennan, George, 2 folders)
  - Kennedy, John F.
    - Debate with Nixon
    - In Germany
    - Interview (Izvestiia)
    - Promises (Box 33)
    - Speeches
      - Acceptance
      - End Cold War, June 11, 1963
      - On Summit, Campaign 1960
  - Kennedy, Joseph P., 2 folders)
  - Kerensky, Alexander F.
    - General
    - Proclamations
  - Kerillis, Henri
  - Kesserling
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S.
    - General
    - Achilles heel (agriculture)
    - Antisemitism
    - Broken promises
    - Conflict with Mao
    - Foreign affairs (1959 article)
    - Interviews
      - On CBS
      - New York Times, 1957
      - With Walter Lippmann
      - With Drew Pearson
      - With C. L. Sulzberger, 1961
    - Party
    - Revokes Lenin
    - Speeches
      - In Baku
      - On Stalin, 2 folders)
    - On Stalin
    - Suspension of nuclear tests
  - Kihss, Peter
  - Kinel, Lola, "How to Answer Communists"
  - Kinsey Report, The (Box 34)
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter, The, February and March 1953
  - Kirk, Alan
  - Kiselev, K. V. (speech at the UN, 1946)
  - Klooga
  - 'Know-nothings'
  - Knox, Frank
    - Addresses
    - Report
  - Koch, Ilse
  - Kohlberg, Alfred
    - General
    - Bill of particulars
    - 17 documents
    - Letters
      - To Brooks Emeny, 1948
      - To Harry S Truman, 1950
    - Platform document, draft 1
    - Red dream
    - Releases, 2 folders)
  - Koischwitz, Max O.
  - "Komintern und U.S.S.R."
  - Korea
    - "1945 to 1948"
    - "Independence"
    - Syngnam Rhee
  - Korean Katyn, 2 folders)
  - Kosenkina, Oksana S.
  - Kranz, Henri B. (his alibi)
  - Kraus, Herbert A.
  - Kraus, Karl (copyright search)
  - Kravchenko, Viktor
    - Interview
    - Law suit, Paris
  - Krock, Arthur, 2 folders)
  - Kroll interview, 2 folders) (Box 35)
  - Kuh, Frederick
  - Kunze, Gerhardt Wilhelm
  - "Kurdish Independence and Russian Expansion" (by W. L. Westermann)
  - Kuusinen, Otto
  - Labor - United States
    - General
    - Labor Management Conference
  - Lacy, Hugh de
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello H., 2 folders)
  - Lamont, Corliss
  - Land, Emory S.
  - "The Land of the Dead"
  - Lande, Adolf
  - Lane, Arthur Bliss, 2 folders)
  - Lange, Oscar
  - Langerhans, Heinz
  - Laski, Harold J.
  - Latin America
  - Lattimore, Owen
    - 1951
    - F. V. Field investigation
    - Greets 'Living Buddha'
    - Memorandum on China
    - Trial
  - Lauzanne, Stephane
  - Laval, Pierre
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Trial
  - League of Nations
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Mandates
  - Leahy, William D.
  - Leaks
  - Lehman, Henry H.
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Lehmann-Russbueldt, Otto
  - Leisegang, Hans von, "Der Geist des Marxismus"
  - Leith-Ross, Frederick, Sir
  - Lemkin, Raphael
    - Interview, 2 folders)
    - Revision of German genocide law
  - Lend-lease operations (1941-1945)
  - Leon, Maurice
  - Leontjew, Konstantin
  - Lerner, Max
    - General
    - On Freud
  - Lest We Forget, 2 folders)
  - Lestchinsky, Jacob
  - Letters to the editor, 2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Leviero, Anthony
  - Levine, Issac Don
  - Lewis, Brackett
  - Lewis, Fulton, Jr.
  - Ley, Robert
  - Liber, Michel and Gotz, Abram
  - Liberal International
  - Liberia
  - Liberty Ships
  - Lidice
  - Lie, Trygve
    - General
    - Won't intervene in China
  - Lilienthal, David E. - Statement
  - Lincoln, Abraham (150th anniversary of his birth)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Linse, Walter
  - Lippmann, Walter
    - General
    - "Electing a President"
    - On him
    - Interview
  - Lipschutz, Isidore
  - Lithuania
  - Lithuanian American Council of Societies
  - Lithuanian American Information Center
  - Lithuanian Bulletin
  - Litvinov, Maxim
    - General
    - Interview with Hottelet
  - Llano, Queipo de
  - Lloyd's
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 2 folders)
  - Lodgman von Auen
  - Logan Act
  - Lommer, Horst
  - London
    - General
    - London Conference, 1945 ('breakdown conference')
  - Lonigan, Edna
  - Lop, Ferdinand
  - Losses
  - Lost thrones
  - Lourie, Donald Bradford
  - Lovestone, Jay
  - Low, David
  - Lowenstein, Hubertus
  - Lowenthal, Fritz
  - Lozovsky, S. A.
  - Lublin (death factory)
  - Lublin-Committee, Recognition of, by U.S.S.R.
  - Ludecke, Kurt G. W.
  - Ludwig, Emil
  - Lukacs, Georg
  - Lyons, Eugene
    - General
    - "Our New Privileged Class"
  - Lyttelton, Oliver
  - MacArthur, Douglas (Box 37)
    - General
    - Bigart's accusations and MacArthur's answer
    - Controversy with Washington, D.C., 2 folders)
    - Hearing
      - General
      - MacArthur's speech in Texas, 2 folders)
      - Statements by
        - Acheson, 10 folders)
        - Bradley, 5 folders)
        - Collins, 2 folders)
        - Hurley, 2 folders)
        - Johnson
        - Lodge
        - Marshall and Truman, 7 folders)
        - O'Donnell
        - Sherman, 2 folders)
        - Vandenberg, 2 folders)
        - Wedemeyer, 3 folders)
      - Verdict of 8 Senators
    - Keynote speech, GOP Convention, 1952 (Box 38)
    - Ouster, 3 folders)
    - 'Triumph'
    - The unanswered question
  - Macedonia
  - Machrowicz, Thaddeus M. (speech at the Democratic Convention, 1952)
  - Madariaga, Salvador de
  - Magna Carta, 1215
  - "Magna Carta for Refugees"
  - Mahan, Lyle Evans
  - Maidanek (death factory)
  - Malenkov, Georgi
    - H-bomb
    - Purges
  - Malik, Charles
    - Quaker interview
    - Question to him
    - Statement (UN, 1949)
  - Mallon, Paul (Box 39)
  - Man, Henry de
  - Manchuria
  - Mandates (League of Nations)
  - Mandl, Fritz
  - Manhattan
  - Mann, Eric
  - Mann, Erika
  - Mann, Klaus
    - General
    - Obituaries
  - Mann, Thomas
    - General
    - "Friedrich und die grosse Koalition" (excerpts)
    - Letter to Julius Epstein, October 23, 1939
    - Tillinger article
  - Mansfield (Berlin speech of June 14, 1961)
  - Manstein, Feldmarschall von
  - Manuilski, Dmitri
  - Mao Tse-tung (letter of June 14, 1963)
  - Maps
    - General
    - U.S.
      - General
      - N.Y. State and New England
      - Road maps (Box 40)
      - Washington, D.C.
    - World
  - March, H. F.
  - Marcantonio, Vito
  - Maril, Konrad
  - Markos, General
  - Marlio, H. See Moulton, H. G.
  - Marshall, George C.
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Letters to Governor Dewey
    - Plan, 3 folders)
    - Report
    - On War with Russia
  - Martin, David
  - Marx on panslavism
  - Marzani Case
  - Masaryk, Jan
    - General
    - Suicide letter, 4 folders)
  - Masaryk, T. G.
  - Massing, Hede
  - Material and excerpts
  - Material to be ordered
  - Matthews, Joseph B., 3 folders)
  - Mau, Hermann
  - Mayerling
  - Mae, Dr.
  - McCarran Committee
    - General
    - Communist propaganda in the U.S. (Box 41)
    - Espionage activities
    - Institute of Pacific Relations - Investigation, 2 folders)
  - McCarran-Walter Bill
  - McCarthy, Joseph R.
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Hearings
      - Majority and minority reports
      - Tydings Subcommittee
    - Interview with Cosmopolitan Magazine
    - "McCarthyism, the Fight for America"
    - Releases
    - Scandal, 2 folders)
    - Speeches (Box 42)
      - General
      - On General Marshall
    - State Department's answers
    - Time magazine cover story
  - McCloy, John J.
    - General
    - Stuttgart speech, February 6, 1950
  - McCormick, Anne O'Hare
  - McDaniel, C. Yates
  - McLeod, Scott
  - McNamara, Robert S. (interview)
  - McNeil, Hector
  - Medicine
  - Medina's charge
  - Meissner, Otto
  - Meitner, Lise
  - Melish, William H.
  - Menne, Bernhard, "The case of Dr. Bruening"
  - Menon, Krishna
  - Martens, Heinrich
  - Messerschmitt, Willy
  - Metzsch, Horst von
  - Mexico
  - Meyer, Conrad
  - Michael, King of Romania
  - Mikhailovitch, Drazha
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Press clippings
    - Trial
  - Mikoyan, Anastas I.
    - General
    - Press conference
  - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw
    - General
    - Escape from Poland
  - The Militant
  - Mill, John Stuart
  - Milrud
  - Mindszenty, Joseph, Cardinal
    - General
    - Koltan Czaky's book on him
  - Minquiers & Ecrehou
  - 'Minutenkaufkraft'
  - Mises, Ludwig von
  - Missile debate
  - Mitchell, Ruth
  - Moats, Alice-Leon
  - Molnar, Ferenc
  - Molotov, Vyacheslav (Box 43)
    - General, 2 folders)
    - 1962
    - And Vishinsky
  - Mondorf, Luxemburg (German chiefs learn about U.S. atomic bomb)
  - Money. "Know Your Money"
  - Monte Cassino
  - Montgomery, Lord
  - Montgomery Ward
  - Montreux Convention, July 20, 1936
  - Morawetz, V. N., Mrs. (assignments)
  - Morgan, J. P.
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr.
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Sr.
  - Morocco
  - Moscow
    - Atrocity Declaration
    - Conferences, 1943 and 1945
    - Meeting, 1960
    - National Committee
  - Moulton, H. G. and Marlio, H., "Can Germany Be 'Controlled' into Being Peaceful?"
  - Mountbatten, Louis, Viscount
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott
  - Muhlen, Norbert, 2 folders)
  - Murphy, Robert
  - Murphy, Tom (on crime)
  - Mussolini, Benito
    - General
    - Against war
    - Death, 2 folders)
    - Interview with Maugeri
    - Son
  - Mutual funds
  - Nadolny, Rudolf
  - Naft, Stephen
    - General
    - "Questions for Communists"
    - Research for Morse
  - Nagorski, Zygmunt, Jr.
  - NAM 1961
  - Naples
  - Nasser, Gamal Abdel (Time magazine cover story)
  - Nathan, Reuben
  - The Nation (85th Anniversary edition), "Peace with Russia. Can It Be Negotiated?"
  - National Archives (list and guides) (Box 44)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 2 folders)
  - National Committee for Free Europe, Inc.
    - General
    - "Stop Stalin's Big Lie"
  - National Socialism (State Department report)
  - NATO history
  - Nazis
    - Admissions
    - Alibis
    - Boasting (promises, predictions)
    - Bund revivivus
    - Camouflage
    - Elite
    - Fehme
    - Foreign policy
    - Saboteurs
    - In South America
  - Near East
  - "The Necessary War" (J. E.), 2 folders)
  - Necker, Wilhelm, 2 folders)
  - Nelson, Donald M.
    - General
    - Report on China
  - Nenni, Pietro
  - Nepal
  - Netschajew, Serge
  - The Network, 2 folders)
    - General
    - General, 2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Concerning Hans Berger
  - Neubacher, Hermann
  - Neue Zeit (Moscow)
  - Neue Zeitung (Lehmann case)
  - Neumann, Margarete
  - The New Leader
    - General, 2 folders)
    - First magazine issue
  - 'New Look'
  - News background
  - Newspaper strike
  - New U.S. directive to General Clay
  - New weapons
  - New York history
  - New York Herald Tribune High School Forum, March 1950
  - New York Post (Box 46)
  - New York Times
    - Biographies
    - Blunders, 2 folders)
    - 100 year edition
    - Pro Roosevelt editorial
    - Headlines, 2 folders)
    - Statement of ownership, 1950
    - Time magazine controversy
  - New York World Telegram and The Sun
  - Nicolaevsky, Boris (on struggle in the Kremlin)
  - Niedermayer, Oskar von
  - Nitti, Francesco
  - Nixon, Richard (television speech)
  - Nizer, Louis
  - Noack, Ulrich
  - Nobel Prize
    - Candidates, 1952
    - Winner dinner
  - Norden, Heinz
  - Norimas, Andrius, "From Lithuania to Death in the Katyn Forests"
  - Normandy
  - North Atlantic Treaty, 5 folders)
  - Norway
  - Nowy Swiat (Polish newspaper)
  - Novikov, N. V., 2 folders)
  - Operation: Candy Drop
  - Nuclear energy (peaceful use)
  - Nuremberg Trial
  - Nuremberg Trial, 4 folders) (Box 47)
  - Nurnberg, Ralph
  - Nurnberg, Rudolph (Trenker-plagiat)
  - Oath at the Elbe
  - Oatis, William N.
  - Occupation statute for West Germany, 1949
  - Odessa Catacombs
  - O'Donnell, John
  - Oechsner, Frederick O. (on Hitler)
  - Oertzen, F. W.
  - Official documents issued during the two world wars
  - Oil
  - Olivetti-Underwood
  - Olshansky, Boris
    - Deposition
    - "Why I Turned Anti-Communist"
  - Oltmans, Willem L.
  - "One World or None"
  - O'Neill, Eugene Gladstone
  - Oppenheimer, Robert-case
  - Orlov, Alexander
  - Osovnik, Anthony
  - Otepka, Otto-case
  - Orlando, Vittorio Emanuele
  - OSS
  - Oswiecim concentration camp. See Auschwitz
  - Otto, Archduke (Box 48)
  - Oumansky, Constantine
  - Overland, Arnulf
  - Overseas Branchers
  - Overseas Press Club Dinner (March 3, 1950)
  - O.W.I.
    - General
    - German broadcasts
    - Surveys
  - OWN (The Paulus army on the march)
  - Paine, Mrs. ('Lady Hamilton')
  - Paix et Liberte
  - Palestine
    - General, 2 folders)
    - History, written by King Ibn Saud
    - Report of UN Commission, 1947, 4 folders)
  - Panama (Box 49)
  - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi
  - Pan-Germanism in the U.S.
  - Pan-Germans before 1914
  - Pan-Hispania (J. E.)
  - Panikkar, Kavalam Madava
  - Papanek, Jan
  - Papen, Franz von
  - Pares, Bernard, Sir, 2 folders)
  - Park East
  - Pasternak, Boris (concerning Olga Vsevolodnaya Ivinskaya)
  - Pat, Jacob
  - Pauker, Ana
  - Paul, Rudolf (Minister President of Thuringian)
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Letter, Washington Post
  - Pauling, Linus
  - Paulus, Friedrich von
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Expected back in Berlin
  - Pax Romana
  - Peace making, Patterns of
  - Peace treaties
    - General
    - With satellites
  - "Peace and War: United States Foreign Policy, 1931-1941"
  - Pearl Harbor
    - General
    - Report
  - Pearson, Drew - Column
  - Pechel, Rudolf
  - Peffer, Nathaniel
  - Pegler, Westbrook
    - Column of January 20, 1953
    - On him
  - Peking-Bonn trade agreement, 1963
  - Pell, Herbert
  - Pentagon
  - People & Freedom
  - Pepper, Claude, 2 folders)
  - Peru
  - Petain, Henri-Philippe
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Death
    - Trial
  - Peter the Great (his will) (Box 50)
  - Peters, Richard F.
  - Philippines
  - Phillips, William - Report on Indian situation
  - Photographs. See also Bissell, Clayton L.; Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940; Minolta 16; "Operation Keelhaul"; Own photographs (J. E.); Peter and Pat; Polonia Restituta (negatives); United Nations; Vlasov, General (negatives)
    - Army, Navy, Air Force, Atomic Energy Commission
    - Department of Defense, Thule
    - German atrocities in Poland
    - Guggenheim Museum
    - Heuss, Theodor
    - International Automobile Exhibition, N.Y., 1959
    - Mikhailovitch, Drazha
    - Rauschning, Hermann
    - R.C.A., New York
    - Switzerland, 4 folders)
    - Switzerland, 2 folders) (Box 51)
    - Thompson Ramo Wooldridge, Inc.
    - Tregellas, Pat (accordian artist)
    - United Nations
    - Sofvoto
  - Physician-pharmacist on the stage
  - Pintschovius, Karl
  - Pirogov, Peter
  - Pius XII, Pope
    - General
    - Address on the creation of the universe
    - Apostolic letter to peoples of Russia
    - Catholic opinion
    - Decree against communism
    - On him
    - Speeches, addresses
  - Plagiarism racket
  - Playwrights' Company
  - PM, 2 folders)
  - Pol, Heinz
  - Poland
    - General
    - W. H. Chamberlin's article
    - Under Stalin
    - Underground
  - Poles
    - American, 2 folders)
    - In Congress
    - In exile, 2 folders)
  - Polish American Congress (press clippings)
  - Polish border issue
  - Polish facts and figures